

About Me

Design Lead - UI/UX, with 8+ years of robust experience in crafting beautiful and easy to use interfaces for websites, mobile applications, business cards, brochures, flat icons, and brandings. Contributed in designing bespoke digital experiences for small bouquets to large blue-chip organisations.

Cater to the needs and goals of users, project managers, developers and testers to ensure the best possible experience.

Contact Details

- afsalrahimanafi@gmail.com
- +91 9746 60 9692
- in www.linkedin.com/in/afsalrahiman
- ◆ Pavayilveedu, Kallingal Kulathoor, Trivandrum, 695583

Portfolio Links

- www.be.net/afsalrahiman92
- www.dribbble.com/afsalrahiman
- www.bit.ly/3NLdRHp (Google Drive)

Career Objective

A quick learner who can absorb new ideas and can communicate clearly and effectively. Currently looking for an opportunity to join a dynamic, ambitious, growing company and forge a career as a first class designer.

Professional Snapshot

Stay updated with latest achievements, best practices and trends

Good team worker and work closely with developers. Take responsibility at all stages of UI design life cycle.

Involved with user experience processes, Creating and assisting with wireframes, Design prototype (Figma, XD, InvisionApp etc), mockups, infographics and video editing.

Work Experience

Design Lead - UI/UX @ Yarab Technologies

January 2019 - Present - Trivandrum, Kerala

Team Management, Web & App UI/UX Designs, Mockups, Corporate Branding Identities and Print Designs

Designs for Facebook Ads, Social media graphics, Flyers.

Creating videos for Website banner, Youtube Ads, Photo slideshow, Logo reveal and Kinetic typography videos.

Creative UI/UX Designer @ Cignitech

March 2018 - January 2019 - Trivandrum, Kerala

Delivered Projects for US, Indian Clients.

Web & App UI/UX Designs, Mockups, Corporate Branding, and Print Designs, Social media graphics, Flyers.

Creating videos for Website banner, Youtube Ads, Photo slideshow, Logo reveal and Kinetic typography videos.

Graphics/UI Designer @ CYBOSOL Infotech

February 2015 - March 2018 - Trivandrum, Kerala

Delivered Projects for UAE, KSA and German Clients.

Responsible for creating various Corporate Presentation including corporate videos, PPT Presentation based on the company guide lines.

Skills

Website, Wireframe, Design & Logo Corporate Branding

Mobile/Web App Design

Video Editing & Kinetic Typography, GIF Animation

Photo Manipulation, Print Design & Graphic Design

Knowledge in HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Tool Skills

Figma	
Adobe XD	
Adobe Photoshop	_
Adobe Illustrator	
Framer	
Adobe After Effects	
Adobe Premiere Pro	
Axure, Balsamiq	
CorelDRAW	
Sketch, Dora	
Adobe Acrobat	

Education

Diploma in Graphic / Web Design
Rays & Hues Animation & Film Academy - Thrissur, Kerala

Higher Secondary

GVHSS CHERPU - Thrissur, Kerala

Secondary School Leaving Certificate

SBHS (Swami Bodhandha High School) - Thrissur, Kerala

Main Projects Worked

Yasref - Yanbu Aramco Sinopec Refining Company

An Intranet Portal for the joint venture (between Saudi Aramco and Sinopec China)

Etlebli - OFOS

Online Food Ordering System - Mobile Application for KSA Client

Beam - Creative Science Schools

Beam is known for its excellence in operating the US & UK Dual Curriculum schools across Dubai and Sharjah.

eAssfar

A market place for the Travel industry in UAE. Major services like hotel room booking, flight booking, transportation etc.

Sahlhgo

A consumer mobile application to do transaction with vendor, and to pay utilities bill etc.

Live link: https://bit.ly/3qdykdb

Marex Composites

Global organization that distributes and finishes structural core materials company in Dallas, Texas

Live link: https://www.marexcompositesinc.com/

Dhahran Tower

Dhahran Tower, is a unique Residential Skyscraper in the heart of Al Khobar

Live link: https://dhtower.com/

Smart Cover Insurance

A Complete insurance service provider in UK Live link: https://smart-cover.co.uk/

Smart Sure Business Insurance

A Complete insurance service provider in UK Live link: https://business.smart-sure.com/

Cover My Gadgets

A Complete Gadget insurance service provider in UK Live link: https://covermygadgets.com/

SCS Marine Global

Cleaning Service company in UAE Live link: https://scsmarineglobal.com/

City & Commercial Group

Provide end-to-end insurance, Underwriting solutions. Live link: https://cityandcommercial.com/

Rentome

Digital Property Letting Agency in UK Live link: https://www.rentome.co.uk/

And Much More..

Personal Details

Date of Birth 12 - May - 1995

Marital Status
Single

Passport Number W8861231

Hobbies

Innovating new design techniques

Listening Music

Photography

Photo/Video Editing

Reading Technical Blogs

Penetration Testing

Gaming Activities

Creating Trolls, Mems

Awards

Film poster design competition winner
Rays & Hues Animation & Film Academy - Thrissur

Best Performer Award
CYBOSOL InfoTech - Trivandrum

Best Performer Award

Yarab Technologies - Trivandrum

Declaration

I hereby declare that the above furnished are true to the extremity of my knowledge and belief